Rachel Stark

Keller, Texas | 817-523-8502 | rstark.smith@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio

ABOUT ME

Full Stack Developer with experience in ReactJS, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript, and I hold a formal BS in Interior Design. Currently pursuing a UX Design certification through Grow with Google, I bring a comprehensive skill set to the table. With exceptional communication and collaboration abilities, I have developed a strong understanding of user and stakeholder needs. As a result of my approach, my designs consistently achieve the ideal blend of functionality and visual appeal, all while prioritizing the user experience.

SKILLS

React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Rails, SQL, GitHub, Framer, TailwindCSS, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, VS Code, TypeForm, SurveyMonkey, GoogleForms, Slack, Zoom, Ideation, Prototyping, User Research, Personas, User-Centered Design, Client Intake, Meeting Facilitation, Public Speaking, Presentations, Conflict Resolution, Stakeholder Engagement, Team Collaboration, Managing Up, Design Fundamentals, Cross-functional Work

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

nosh.up - Github | Demo | Live - ReactJS | Ruby on Rails Foodie photo sharing application for food truck cuisine

Implemented Active Storage using AWS S3 for user photo storage

ShelfieShare - Github | Demo - ReactJS | Ruby on Rails

Reading community application that allows readers to share books, reviews and photos of their "To Be Read" bookshelf

User authentication at sign in, including password protection using BCrypt

Fox Vinyl - Github | Demo - ReactJS | Ruby | Active Record | Sinatra

Record Collection application to keep track of users record inventory and share with other collectors

• Implemented models with a one-to-many relationship, offering users full CRUD capabilities for records

Lego List - Github | Demo - ReactJS

Application designed for Lego enthusiasts to manage and monitor their assembled creations and boxed sets

EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed

Stay-at-home Parent 01/2013 - Current

Freelance Designer

- Interior Design | Managed in-home design and remodels for multiple projects
- Event Planning | Coordinated vendors | Managed budgets | Created timelines | Client communication
- Orchestrated four long distance moves, including the sale of two homes

Crate & Barrel

Plano, Texas

Sales Manager

09/2011 - 08/2012

- Guided furniture representatives with custom furniture sales and maintained vendor communication
- Trained sales associates on products and how to drive sales

VLK Architects

Arlington, Texas

Interior Designer

01/2008 - 12/2009

- Presented design proposals, gathered feedback, and developed solutions that prioritized clients input
- Designed logos, selected finishes, and provided recommendations for creating a cohesive aesthetic
- Reviewed and drafted product specifications, used AutoCAD and SketchUp to contribute to construction documents

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Remote Flex Program

Full Stack Web Development Certificate, Ruby on Rails, React, JavaScript

03/2022 - 05/2023

Grow with Google UX Design Certificate Online Flex Program expected 09/2023

University of Texas at Arlington

Bachelor of Science in Interior Design, Cum Laude

Arlington, Texas 12/2007